There is no practical
obstacle whatever now to the
creation of an efficient
index to all human knowledge,
ideas and achievements.
To the creation that is of a complete
planetary memory for all mankind.
He was one of the early
inventors of science fiction.
The idea of time travel,
the possibility
of invisibility...
..of inter-competence.
galactic struggles.
And then he came up with ideas
of how we might reorganise the
knowledge apparatus of the world
which he called the world brain.
For Wells the world brain
had to contain all that was...
learned unknown and that
was being learned unknown.
If you have access to
anything that's been written,
not just theoretical access,
but like instant access
next to your brain,
that changes your
idea of who you are.
It can be reproduced
exactly and fully in Peru,
China,
Iceland,
Central Africa,
or wherever else.
They were frank in their ambition and
dazzling in their ability to execute it.
The
Google Book Scanning
Project is clearly the most
ambitious brain scheme
that has ever been invented.
This is no remote dream,
no fantasy.
It is a plain statement of a
contemporary state of affairs.
There is a danger that Google's
aim is to achieve a monopoly
The nightmare
scenario in 20 years'
time would be Google
tracking everything we read.
Google could basically
hold the whole world hostage.
since
Wells.
Science fiction is always
about the possibility that people
don't really matter in the
future and the plot is always
about some heroic person
that either succeeds or doesn't
succeed in proving that
people really matter after all.
It's a library,
a public library,
where people go to look at books
and read them and take them away.
That girl works at the library
and she checks on books
that are going out and
books that are coming back in.
I love libraries.
I like the smell,
the smell of paper
properly preserved.
It's as if it's the smell of a
hay barn that's been cleared
of all its animals and made
into human intelligence.
And in a library,
you really,
even if you're sitting...
Sitting in the tea room,
discussing your latest findings,
it's amazing how much
social interaction with other
people will actually help you
to enrich what you're doing.
In this part of the library,
the grown-ups can read
the stories to the children.
People sometimes say to me,
aren't libraries obsolete?
It's absurd.
They are nerve centres,
centres of intellectual energy.
Libraries stand for an ideal,
which is an educated public.
And to the degree that
knowledge is power,
they also stand
therefore for the idea that
power should be disseminated
and not centralized.
The first appeal of
Google's enterprise when we saw it was just
digitizing millions and millions of books.
At Harvard we have by far
the greatest university library.
in the world.
It's enormous,
17 million volumes,
and every library wants its
holdings digitized for lots of reasons,
including preservation.
But beyond that,
it raises the possibility of
sharing your intellectual wealth.
I think of the Harvard Library
as an international asset,
something that should be opened up
and shared with the general population.
So here comes Google,
they've got the energy,
they've got the technology,
they've got the money and
they said we'll do it for you,
free.
Google did such a fabulous
job in creating a vision,
not only that a universal
digital library could be created,
but that it could be done today,
the Google.
engineers,
are like good
engineers everywhere.
They just like to think about how
do we surmount these challenges.
They sort of leave the lawsuit
to the lawyers to worry about.
Google's a company that believes
in its fundamental mission of
empowering everyone in this world
with all the information they need.
Enriched with the
right information,
people can make
better decisions for themselves,
their families,
and their communities.
This world is full of wonderful
individuals which have varied needs,
from a farmer in Africa,
to a mother in India,
to a business person in Japan.
Everyone needs information
in this modern day and age.
And Google believes
in breaking all the barrier
between every individual
and the information they seek.
When you actually
negotiate with Google,
and do so on their turf,
you enter a strange world.
A Google office doesn't
have chairs like this chair.
The furniture consists of large inflated
balls that are colored green or red or yellow,
and the young Google
engineers are sitting on these.
It's a kind of Never
Never Land feeling.
About ten years ago,
I got a visit from the vice
president of Google and she walked
into my office and described a
project that Google had in mind,
which was to digitize all the
books in the Harvard Library.
My first thought was,
To put it bluntly,
that maybe they were
smoking something,
because I didn't
think it was possible.
Harvard had been digitizing
books from time to time,
but there were very
limited numbers,
and we didn't do many.
It was a very expensive
and complicated project.
I don't remember exactly,
but it was several hundred
dollars just for a single book.
But they had invented a copying station
that was a lot cheaper and easier to use.
that didn't damage the books,
or at least went out of its
way not to damage the books.
And it seemed to me that
it had a lot of plausibility.
And so we decided
to give it a try.
Every great
library did digitizing,
sometimes on a large scale.
Our Open Collections program
digitized 2.3 million pages.
I mean,
that's big,
but nothing like as big as what
Google attempted to do.
the sheer ambition of
digitizing everything.
In the ancient world,
At the Library of Alexandria
they copied rolls and
tablets and in an attempt
to copy all that was known.
And eventually the library
was destroyed by Julius Caesar.
And the loss of the Library of Alexandria
was an international catastrophe.
The Universal Library has
been talked about for millennia.
There's a kind of a continuity
of development and we mustn't
forget the important role
that libraries and scholars
have always made
for millennia of copying.
And then you see with
the development of printing,
the multiplicity of texts,
the copying of original texts.
It was possible to think in the
Renaissance that you might be able to amass
the whole of published knowledge
in a single room or a single institution.
I have here a monument to French
thought - the Great Encyclopedia
Among the various famous
philosophers involved in this
project, the two leaders
were Diderot and D'Alembert
They wanted to collect all
the knowledge of the day
and put it at the service of freedom
of thought and liberty of conscience
The encyclopedia embodies a
moment of French consciousness
in the middle of the eighteenth
century, at the end of Absolute Monarchy
It paved the way for the intellectual
movement which led to the French Revolution
Then in the
19th century,
you have various suggestions
in France and Belgium
that you can create a
catalog of everything.
What will come
next is microfilm.
And so you start finding
huge microfilming projects.
And so for us,
the Google project was a sort of a natural
extension of that process of development.
Project Gutenberg of Michael
Hart was the first digital library.
He started on the
4th of July in early
1970s going and typing the
Declaration of Independence
so that everybody
could have access to it.
Thousands of volunteers worked from
all over the world to go and build this.
He even had the idea that it
ought to be possible to download
the entire library that he
had created if you wanted it.
And I think it did act as a kind
of example of something that
Later on,
Google and others
took up in a much bigger,
more extensive way.
My name is Raymond
Kurzweil and I'm from Queens,
New York.
When I was 12,
I became fascinated
with pattern recognition.
And as a young teenager,
I did a project to teach computers
how to recognize patterns in music.
I built a computer and by feeding
in certain relationships in music,
I was...
Able to write music with him.
Raymond,
how old are you?
I'm 17.
Do your parents know
what you've been up to?
Recognizing printed letters
was a classical unsolved
problem in the field
of pattern recognition.
And so I created the first OmniFont
optical character recognition.
This was around 1975.
In 1978 we developed
a commercial version.
And we talked about how you could ultimately
scan all books and all printed material.
When automobiles
came along first,
they seemed likely to
become a rich man's monopoly.
They cost upwards
of a thousand pounds.
Henry Ford ought to be all that.
He put the poor man on the road.
We want a Henry Ford today to
modernize the distribution of knowledge,
make good knowledge
cheap and easy,
in this still very ignorant,
ill-educated,
ill-served,
English-speaking world of ours,
which might be the greatest power
on earth for the good of mankind.
We started the
Internet Archive in 1996.
The idea was to have all the published
works of humankind available to everybody.
That this was the
opportunity of our generation.
That,
like the previous generation,
it put a man on the moon.
The Internet Archive had been
completely open with Google.
In fact,
I'd gone and given a
speech that was attended by...
I think all of the senior
executives on how one could
go about building a
digital library of all books,
video.
And I had hoped that there was
going to be a way to work with them,
but that was not to be.
Libraries had signed secret
agreements with Google.
We didn't know what
was really going on.
When they started
coming out as a completely
separate project and
not working with others,
then I started to
become suspicious.
Larry Page,
who founded Google with me,
first proposed that
we digitize all books a
decade ago when we
were a fledgling startup.
Five years later,
in 2004,
Google Books was born.
Despite a number of important
digitization efforts to date,
none have been at a comparable
scale simply because no
one else has chosen to
invest the requisite resources.
If Google Books is successful,
others will follow.
I don't think that Google is aware
of the fact that it's a corporation.
I think Google does think of itself as an
NGO that just happens to make a lot of money.
And they think of themselves as social reformers who just happen to have their stock
traded on stock exchanges and who just happen to have investors and shareholders,
but they do think of themselves as ultimately
being in the business of making the world better.
There are few more irreparable
property losses than vanished books.
Nature,
politics,
and war have always been the
mortal enemies of written works.
Most recently,
Hurricane Katrina dealt a blow
to the libraries of the Gulf Coast.
At Tulane University,
the main library sat
in nine feet of water.
In the
1970s,
The Khmer Rouge regime
in Cambodia decimated
cultural institutions
throughout the country.
Khmer Rouge fighters...
...took over the
National Library,
throwing the books
into the street,
burning them,
while using the
stacks as a pigsty.
Now with Google,
the University of Michigan
is involved in one of the
most extensive preservation
projects in world history.
Google Books is a potent
idea on a number of dimensions.
What I like about Google
Books is the idea of...
Not losing books,
especially books that might
be genuinely abandoned.
The idea of getting
all that stuff online is,
of course,
going to be a benefit.
So that we have to love.
I went to Google
in January 2003.
I actually made what now
I feel quite embarrassed about.
I made a presentation to them,
telling them what
they ought to be doing,
only to find out a few
months later that they'd
actually been doing
it for a while already.
Project Ocean was
the kind of code name,
development code name,
that Google were giving
to what eventually became
Google Books.
So it was called Project
Ocean because it was big,
I imagine.
Google seemed to think that they
could do almost a million in three years.
You could say that this
mass digitization is something
like running a huge
machine through a library.
You take books by the shelf,
they're put in cartons.
on carts,
they're loaded onto trucks,
and then
Google at this time had three places in the
country where it was doing digitization.
Supposedly it didn't
give the address.
of where they were.
Google won't say how much
scanning all the books cost,
but there are estimates that it's
somewhere between $30 and $100 per book.
So if you multiply that times,
$20 million.
Google early on bent
over backwards to keep us
from communicating
with the other libraries.
There were three
or four large ones.
and each of us was told we should not tell
the others what kind of a contract we had.
and how we were
working with Google.
To begin with,
it had to be kept fairly quiet.
It was probably mid-2003 when I
started to take the wraps off in terms of,
this is going to be a possibility that
we might be working with Google.
I witnessed the scale of the
operation and it was very impressive.
20 very large workstations
with very high resolution
cameras sitting on top of
cradle with very intense lights.
and underneath a lot of
black boxes which presumably
contained all of Google's
algorithms that makes
Google search what it is and
they uploaded that stuff straight to
Mountain View straight from
Mozart.
Google certainly depends on
knowing more and more and more
for their algorithm to be
better and better and better.
And this is the core of the way
economics in this space now works.
They had a specific interest in having
lots of things in Google that would lead
people to use Google so they could
make money by having advertisements there.
What are books?
They're full of data.
And so.
So the more data you have,
the more you can fine tune
your search technologies.
Some of the enthusiasts for
Google's way of gathering data,
and it's not just Google at all,
I mean,
it's Silicon Valley in general.
It's the current
cultural moment.
It includes the other
Silicon Valley companies,
but also the modern
world of finance,
and and also the modern
world of spycraft for states,
and also the modern
world of criminality.
in the modern world of
insurance and healthcare.
All these things have this idea
that you grab all this data in order to
You become very powerful.
You create a differential in your
ability to see information versus the
ordinary person and you create
these new incredible castles of power.
But it's okay.
It's not just traditional
power mongering
because you're making
the world more efficient.
I was a little boy in the
70s growing up in India
watching reruns of
Star Trek on our family's
black-and-white TV
and from that those times
the picture of a Star
Trek computer was deeply
ingrained in my head.
As a little boy I was
just fascinated by the fact
that you can walk up
to a computer and ask it,
computer what's the
atmosphere of that planet?
That was just the most
fascinating thing to a little boy.
boy.
And from that day on,
it was my dream to build
that Star Trek computer.
Only later would I
grow up and realize it's
really hard because
computers don't understand
language and I went through this brief period
of disbelief as a graduate student where
I didn't think I would reach
my dream in my lifetime.
But thanks to Google and all the technologies that
we have built here and what I see in the pipeline,
I am closer to my
my dream than ever.
The Internetis a young medium
The only things you
used to be able to find-on
the net were things
specially created for it
but our entire cultural
heritage, all that we know
and that humans have learnt
through history is contained in books
If books were not
available on the Internet
then all of the potential
of the net as a medium to
access information and
knowledge would be limited
Once we began
developing the product our
objective was to incorporate
other types of ontent
published outside the
Anglo-Saxon world and
available in the great
libraries of the world
The library of Montserrat was
founded in the eleventh century
When the monks first arrived they needed
books for prayer and spiritual readings
This is one of the books
digitised in the Google project
the spiritual exercises of
Father Garcia de Cisneros
who was abbot here
in the sixteenth century
He devised exercises to guide
one to a deeper Christian life
On the Internet you can
surf from one web page
to another without
deepening your knowledge
FATHER DAMIA ROU LIBRARY
DIRECTOR, MONASTERY OF MONTSER
FATHER DAMIA ROU LiBrary
Director, MonaStery of Montser
FATHER DAMIA ROU
This book could be interpreted as a
call not to flit from one page to another
without deepening your
spiritual understanding
Google digitised about
23,400 books from this library
It seemed to us that this was
a way of spreading our culture
It gives us a great satisfaction
that they are available to everybody
Google didn't pay you to
scan your books -was that fair?
What happens if someone turns all this
into a business and makes a profit from it?
Perhaps the question
is too difficult?
I am not in a position to comment
on anything other than the digitisation
and the access to these books
from wherever that might be
I mean,
part of our ethos and
part of our objective as a
library is to make the
information that's contained
in our library available
as free of charge as
we can possibly make it
to anybody who needs it.
And if Google is going to
do that on a larger scale,
that's fine.
If they are going to make
money out of it down the line,
why not?
You know,
they've invested
a lot of money in it.
There's no such
thing as a free lunch.
Who wouldn't want to
have all of the world's
knowledge available to
everyone on the planet?
The problem is that
Google, as an
intermediary in this process,
has certain interests and has a certain
agenda that is not always transparent.
If you're in Silicon Valley,
you have another job,
which is you're building this new life
form that's going to take over the world,
and
Google is providing the
memories for its brain,
or the other companies
are providing the memories.
And this is something
that's openly talked about.
It's all human knowledge,
in books and out of books,
woven together.
Into a single entity that's
accessible by anybody,
anywhere in the world,
anytime.
And that all knowledge
is transformative.
It just really kicks up the civilization
in our society into another level.
Shortly after the
launch of Google Books,
in different events,
I ran into Larry Page
and Sergey Brin and had
this brief exchange with
them about the potential.
And there was a characteristic
Google founder response,
which was a kind of glint
in their eyes and a smile,
and the sense that this was
just the beginning of something
much bigger than even
you at this point can imagine.
At Harvard,
we only permitted Google to
digitize books in the public domain.
But the other research
libraries that Google first went to
permitted Google to digitize
books covered by copyright.
As soon as you get
into the copyright area,
things get rapidly complicated.
We're allowing Google
to scan all of our books,
those in the public domain
and those still in copyright.
We believe it is legal,
ethical,
and a noble endeavor that
will transform our society.
Legal,
because we believe
copyright law allows us fair use
of the millions of books
that are being digitized.
Fair use is a piece of
American copyright law that
allows us to make copies
without asking any permission,
without paying any fee
for certain carved out uses.
I happen to think Google's
fair use defense is strong.
One of the things...
that courts have done
over the last decade or so
is decided that search
engines who routinely make
copies of information
are making fair uses when
they do it in order to help
people find information.
information that
they're looking for.
One of the things Google
has done is provide
links to places where
you can buy the book.
They scanned,
but they did not
release the copy.
You could not search
except for keywords.
You could not see a
page except for snippets.
They were trying to allow indexing and
searching without allowing people to get copies.
And we will protect all
copyrighted materials.
your work in that archive,
let me repeat.
I repeat that.
I guarantee you we will
protect all copyrighted materials.
I assure you we understand that providing
public access to materials and copyright,
particularly
those still in print,
would be unlawful.
One of the things that you need to
understand about Google is that they try
to roll out projects first and then to
think about the consequences later.
So you would often see them experiment
with something that looks very cool.
It may be the Google
Street View project.
Google launched
Street View in 2007,
part of the search
engine's long-term goal to
create a virtual 3D
map of the whole planet,
right down to street level.
But investigations have revealed
that Google's Street View cars
were collecting more than just
photographs for their databanks.
Their antennas were also
hoovering up personal information.
from unencrypted Wi-Fi networks,
including Internet
history and passwords.
I think the case of...
Google collecting
Wi-Fi information.
It reveals a complete lack of respect
for privacy within the corporation.
Such projects often reveal that
Google does not fully understand the
social consequences of its own work.
We actually do more
search queries in China alone.
than any other search company
does in any other single national market,
by which I really mean
Google in the United States.
So we certainly do
aspire to be a world brand.
I think H.G.
Wells was,
I mean,
he's well known for
having been quite prescient
about a lot of the things
that he envisioned.
I'm sure we don't have
a time machine yet,
but pretty much the
rest of it was dead on.
We have a product
which is a very,
very popular product.
It's called Baidu Wenku.
The Chinese name of
it is the Baidu Library.
It allows people to upload.
materials that they have that
are either of their own creation or
that they have the intellectual
property rights to to our site.
We mainly scan books for schools and
universities, and some for individual professors
Each person here scans
about 30 books a day on average
ER STAR BOOK SCANNING CEN
CHUNLEI PER STAR
BOOK SCANNING CENTRE
The number of books
we scan is increasing
every year. At first it
was only Chinese books
but now we are scanning foreign
books and magazines as well
When we started we just had
one scanning centre in Beijing
but now we have 17
scanning centres across China
We can store more information if we
scan it and preserve data for the future
area of human knowledge
that hasn't been filled out and
made more rich and wondrous
by the fact of the internet.
I'm often just sort of
shocked at people who see it
as the beginnings of this
sort of dystopian future.
I embrace it unequivocally.
The fundamental knowledge
system which accumulates,
sorts,
keeps in order,
and renders available
everything that is known,
centers on Barcelona with
its 17 million active workers.
It is the memory of mankind.
This is the Marenostrum
supercomputer. It has 10,000 processors
Drdi torres OFESSOR,
UPC BARCELONA TECH
JRDI TORRES Ofessor,
Upc Barcelona Tech
RDI TORRES
DRDI TORRES Dfessor,
Upc Barcelona Tech
That's like 10,ooo laptops that have all
been put together with their hard disks
It's changing our day-to-day
lives, the way we work and interact
his record,
he's changing our daily life,
our way of working,
interacting.
creations and that in a real
sense that there is more of
God in a cell phone than there
is in a tree frog because a cell
phone is an additional layer of
evolution over the natural frog.
Big corporations are
amassing information about
us, information that
we're not even aware of
that they constantly use
for their own purposes
The amount of data is
generating a bottleneck
Storing this data is a
problem. And the methods
we've been using up
till now no longer work
We need to find a completely
new approach, and this is
part of the research we're
conducting at this centre
And part of the research that is
done in this centre is precisely this.
to give their data in
service of worship of this
new digital god and I
think it's really really dumb.
Has this computer been placed in the
middle of a church for any special reason?
Its one of life's coincidences.
But I think it was a good idea
This may not be the
fastest computer in the
world, but it is certainly
the most beautiful
It's not unique to this era.
You can look at...
Previous technologies,
whether it was radio,
whether it was television,
whether it was the telegraph,
whether it was electricity,
you do have many
similar hopes that those
technologies will bring
universal communication,
people will talk to one another,
there will be peace everywhere,
education will spread globally.
A lot of similar hopes
have been expressed.
in connection to
earlier technology.
So this is nothing new,
but I think there is something about the
scale at which projects and groups and various
Companies and organizations now are putting
those cyber utopian beliefs to work.
That is different now than
from what it was before.
DOGL E'S EARTH"
BY WIL AUG 35 200
We are its unpaid content
providers in one way or another.
We generate product for Google.
Our every search a
minuscule contribution.
Google is made of us,
a sort of coral reef of human
minds and their products.
We have yet to take
Google's measure.
A couple of Google reps came to visit
me They were well-behaved young people
They'd obviously
swapped their jeans for ties
because they thought that
would be better in Europe
They had a kind of arrogance
and a spirit of brutal commercialism
They misread my psychology so
badly that they brought me a small gift
a thermo flask, which keeps
your tea warm on train journeys
looked at these young
men, I dropped the gift,
and suddenly I could
see in their expressions
that these salesmen had miscalculated
what kind of commercial target I was
They clearly had no idea who the President
of the National Library of France was
I do think that Google genuinely
wants to make all of the world's
information organized and available
to people throughout the globe.
I do think that they genuinely
believe in that mission.
But they also happen to believe
that nothing will get lost and no
one will get harmed if it's Google
who will implement that mission.
And I think it's normal.
If they didn't trust
themselves to do it,
then they would be,
you know,
they would have some
weird schizophrenic problem.
They don't trust themselves
to implement their own project.
The challenge posed
by Google's thunderclap
announcement to build
a universal digital library
and to do that by itself - this challenge
required a very swift and clear response
A few days later, I held a
meeting with my team of
librarians and the technicians
of the National Library
I decided to plan a counter-offensive,
yes a counter-offensive
I wrote an article in Le Monde with the
headline: “When Google Challenges Europe”
This also became the title
for the book I later published
What disturbed me was that if you
typed in Victor Hugo, Cervantes or Goethe,
19 of the 20 search results
you got were in English
I know they corrected it later
of course but it was alarming
cam out what expect
from France was date.
This was really par a plus
state to make English
the universal language
and as we know the most important
think about France the side from the mind
is it language and there
was a real sens that
who are we
to be Digitized All
those books en anglais
And I remember some
correspondence about the fact that
we at Harvard were not
just digitizing English books,
but were digitizing a very
large number of books in French,
to which,
if I remember correctly,
the response came back,
who are you to digitize
books in French?
It's a battle.
It is a battle. This
is combat, always
I see nothing negative in the word "combat"
There are noble battles and noble conflicts
First,
we learned that Google
was scanning books.
And I remember loving that idea,
because I'm a reader,
and I write nonfiction books,
and I do research,
and
I wanted access to those books.
Then we heard that they
were scanning our books.
They were scanning
copyrighted books,
and they hadn't asked
anyone's permission.
The libraries had
just handed them over.
Well,
that was obviously a
violation of our copyrights,
and a little bit of a surprise.
Put it mildly.
I remember being very curious
about what they were doing,
and I popped my name into Google and saw
that it came up with snippets of my book.
So what I did was I searched for terms
that I knew were common in the book,
like star or galaxy.
And there were
lots and lots of hits,
and it would display
several snippets.
And then
I would search for
other common words.
And it was clear that if you
were clever about your searches,
you could see
quite a bit of the text,
if not all of it.
The problem that most
authors have is obscurity.
That's the issue.
There are a gazillion books.
How do you get people
to pay attention to yours?
Google claimed that its use
of these millions of copyrighted
books that it had digitized
was an example of fair use.
Why?
I'm not sure.
I still don't understand
how that can be justified.
The point is that.
The entire book has been copied,
and it's been copied by
a single company that's
doing it for purposes
of profiting off the work.
If you allow a profit-making
company to copy a million books,
then how can you say
no to the next enterprise
that also wants to
copy the million books?
So the Authors Guild organized a class
action suit asking them to stop doing that.
The Authors Guild on Tuesday filed a
lawsuit against search engine Google.
alleging that its scanning
and digitizing of library
books constitutes a massive
copyright infringement.
The Authors Guild represents
more than 8,000 authors and is
the largest society of published
writers in the United States.
When Google made its decision
to scan these millions of books,
it certainly realized that depending
upon how litigation developed,
this could be a
bet-the-company decision,
because copyright
liability in the United States
can be quite extreme,
$150,000 per copyrighted work.
And depending on the number
of copyrighted works at stake,
it could be in the
billions of dollars.
The Association of American Publishers
has filed a lawsuit against Google,
alleging the internet companies
plan to scan and digitally distribute the
text of major library collections
would violate copyright protections.
I think the issue of
copyright is an archaic,
unproductive view.
When you create something,
you're building on the
work of other people,
no matter who you are,
whether you're
J.K. Rowling or Shakespeare.
You're basing your work
on the work of others.
You're basically
taking their ideas.
Artists does not
own their ideas.
No artist does.
Any useful information is...
exists because of the
efforts of real people.
Copyright is our way of
remembering who those people are.
It's crucial to not lose that.
I think cyber culture is
missing the point of copyright.
You might say,
well,
who cares about authors?
Let a few authors not make as
much money as they would have.
But it's a precedent.
The whole Internet will become a
tool for the concentration of power,
and that would be a disaster.
is
The world's largest copy machine and
anything that touches it is being copied.
And just to transmit
something along the way,
people are making
copies of things.
Copies are valueless.
They have no worth at all.
And so there's a focus on copies
because that's an industrial age artifact.
In 2o07 I discovered that a lot
of our books had been digitised
in das Berufsleben kleidet, und
dies in dem Bereich veranschaulichen
wollen, in dem die- se am
deutlichsten zutage tritt oder.
besser gesagt, am einfachsten
dargestellt werden In 20o7 I
discovered that a lot of our'books
had been digitised Rezensionen
by Google Book Search
without us being asked
And then it turned out that, just from the
one publishing company which prints my books
over 200 books had been scanned by Google
without any permission being obtained
This is about a serious
company which acts illegally
on such a massive
scale that it appears legal
In 2007 I wrote my article, which
not only pointed out the legal issues
but also pointed out the abysmal
quality of the scans of the books
but also pointed out the abysmaleame
back, quality of the scans of the books
You see hands of
the scanner-operators
or a third of the page is
corrupted, so the scans are useless
or a third of the page is corrupted,
ang off so the scans are useless
It's like you make a very delicate
piece of art, ran where every detail counts
but what comes out on
Google Book Search is as if
they had put this work of
art through a meat grinder
but what comes out on
Google Book Search is as if
they had put this work of
art through a meat grinder
this is what I can offer.
A book is not just
an extra long tweet.
A book is something
that's hard to do,
it's hard to finish,
it's hard to publish,
it's a certain
achievement of scale,
it's a declaration of this is
what my life has learned,
this is what I can offer.
And that is not something
that can be dissected and the
little minced pieces simply
can't mean the same thing.
The lawsuits were
commenced in the fall of 2005.
And within six months,
the
Authors Guild and the
publishers came to Google
with a proposal about
settling the lawsuit.
I was sitting
innocently in my office,
and a lawyer for the
university appeared,
and he said,
you are about to take
a non-disclosure oath.
Well,
I've never had anything to do with lawyers
except once in my life when I made a will,
and I thought,
oh,
I'm in deep water now.
What is this all about?
Well,
it turned out that there were
secret negotiations between
Google on the one hand
and the Authors Guild and
the Association of American
Publishers on the other.
They were suing
Google for infringement of
copyright and as happens
frequently with suits.
they began to
negotiate a settlement.
Well,
we were not part
of that at Harvard.
However,
we had to be informed about
it because we had the books.
It took three years to work it out because
there were a lot of issues to be discussed.
There were publishers at
the table as well as authors,
and publishers and authors
did not have identical interests.
There were libraries not at the
table but very much in the picture.
They were talking to
Google away from the room.
And I'm not sure
how much I can say.
I definitely cannot talk specifically
about the negotiations because
I signed a
non-disclosure agreement,
which I'm told
is still in force,
and I don't want to go to jail.
Google's long-running
legal battle with the U.S.
publishing industry came to an unexpected
halt this morning as the parties announced
a settlement that will see both sides cooperate
on online access to copyrighted books.
Google have agreed to pay
$125 million in the settlement.
$34.5 million of that sum will
go towards the establishment
of a rights-collecting
body for digital books.
$45 million has been set
aside to compensate writers
whose copyrighted books
Google has already scammed.
They will get
around $60 per book.
The largest portion
of the settlement,
$45.5 million,
will go just on the legal fees.
But
The most striking aspect of the agreement
is that it turns Google into a bookseller,
selling online
access to out of print,
but still in copyright works.
For those of you who don't know the
details of the settlement agreement,
it's
385 pages.
It has 46 sections
of definitions.
It's got
15 sections on
Google's obligations.
It's got nine sections
on the economic terms.
It's got six sections
on libraries obligations.
So this is not a little three
or four page memorandum
of understanding that
we're talking about here.
This is a very heavily
negotiated agreement.
So how many people have
not read the 334 pages?
Okay.
We proposed something that
was a little bit outside the box,
and that was if
money is being made,
share the money
with the rights holders.
It couldn't be simpler.
So I thought it would be
pretty non-controversial.
apparently was naive of me.
I personally became
increasingly disenchanted
with what originally
looked like a great idea.
They basically transformed the search service
into a gigantic commercial enterprise.
They really thought they
would digitize every book in
existence and make it
available for a price everywhere.
They really thought they would
Digitized every book en existence
and make it available
for a price everywhere.
Settlement would allow
Google to have essentially a
license to commercialize
all books that are out of print.
There were certainly hundreds of thousands
and probably millions of books for whom...
Even if they were in copyright,
no author,
no publisher,
no rights holder
would come forward.
And those books are orphans,
and Google would be
able to commercialize those,
and nobody else would.
A monopoly was being created,
a monopoly of
access to knowledge.
Did we want the greatest
library that would ever
exist to be in the hands
of one giant corporation,
which could really charge almost
anything it wanted for access to it?
It's not a library,
it's a bookstore.
And,
you know,
sell it as a
bookstore if you want,
but don't pretend
that it's a library.
When I talk to people
in the publishing industry,
they find it humorous
because it's like,
well,
they're orphaned for a reason.
And that,
in fact,
if we suddenly found
this gold mine where the
future of the book are
the orphaned books,
OK,
then boy,
those publishers
sure aren't very smart.
Today in this in this
is that under the propose
settlement Google would be
the only nt they could treat copyright
as en opt-out mecanisme everyone
else would have to treated as opt-in
their other from with this propose
edited.
Listed below are various
potential revenue streams
for Google as identified
within the settlement.
institutional subscriptions,
consumer purchases,
advertising uses,
public access service,
print on demand,
custom publishing,
PDF downloads,
consumer subscription model,
summaries,
abstracts,
compilations of books.
That's what you're going
to end up with at a minimum.
What I'm saying to you,
Mr.
Drummond,
does this in fact place Google
at such a tremendous advantage?
In disregard of what has
been historically copyright law,
how do you respond
to those concerns?
As of today,
we have zero market
share in any sort of books.
So we're a new
entrance to the market.
So far,
far from being someone
who's controlling the market,
we're not even in it yet.
We're trying to get in there.
They thought that all we have to do
is kind of announce this to the world,
and the world will go,
God,
what a great agreement.
And for a while,
some people did,
but then you started reading
the agreement really carefully.
and
There were lots of questions.
while some people did, but then
you started reading the agrement
really careful and there
were lutz questions.
There was
nothing in the
agrément that respect
the privacy of the people
who are looking at the book.
how long they were reading it,
Google was going
to be keeping track
who exactly was reading
that book how long they
were reading it and what
they raid next that information
could get back to the government
could get back to the F.B.I.
Could get back to please could
get back to their employeur.
Causes.
Google wasn't making any kind of garanties
what they were gonna do in respect
this privacy.
If people find that the
privacy policies of a
particular technology
are not to their liking,
they should unplug it.
They should retreat
from the internet.
They should cut off their phone lines and
they should go up and hide in a mountain.
They have that choice.
Wells'
conception of a whirl vein
was that it was intended
to have a power of
surveillance over mankind.
Information gathered and
organized in such a way that we had
an eye that could actually survey
everything that was going on.
It would be able to register
where everybody was,
everywhere they went,
potentially all the transactions
that they were engaged in.
And he seemed to think this
is likely to be a good thing.
It was a gradual process of getting to
know the details of Google Book Search,
and it was the cumulative
effect of these details that
made me feel this project
was actually something that
I myself could not recommend
to the President and fellows
of Harvard as something that
we should enthusiastically...
support.
H.G.
Wells'
idea of the world brain was a dictatorship
of technologists and intellectuals.
These are the
geeks of their day.
And gradually he saw their power
would spread from laboratory to laboratory,
from university to university.
These people with the
expertise began to coalesce
into sort of almost
like managerial groups.
That would mean that we don't need the
politicians and the conflicts and the noise,
the confusion,
the babble.
But for the world brain there
was to be a further component,
and this is the component
that is what disturbs me,
it's how that would be used
to achieve the ultimate goals
of civilization as it appears to
have been evolving towards.
The snippets are just
what you see on the surface
The question is: What is a company
doing withall the data I have produced?
If they are simply inputting my texts
into their databases, that is illegal
whether they have a
visible web interface or not
You understand? Because they are doing
it for commercial and not private ends
People are going to ask,
how did it do that?
How did it accomplish
this task which before
we thought only humans
could ever hope to do?
David Hume held this
view that sense and
experience are the sole
foundation of knowledge.
Watson.
What is empiricism?
After IBM's success
with Deep Blue,
they looked around for other kinds
of games that they could take on.
And they wanted
something that was...
a very different kind
of game than chess.
And so they picked Jeopardy,
which is basically
a fancy trivia game.
It's one of those games
that you and I can play.
It's a human standing there with
their carpet and water versus the
computer with all of its silicon
and its main memory and its disk.
After Germany
invaded the Netherlands,
this queen,
her family,
and cabinet fled to London.
Maria.
Who is Beatrix?
No.
Watson.
Who is Wilhelmina?
That is correct.
This US president negotiated
the Treaty of Portsmouth,
ending the Russo-Japanese War.
Watson.
Who is Theodore Roosevelt?
I did talk to Larry Page
when Google first started,
because I was really perplexed
about why would anybody
make a new search engine
when we had AltaVista,
which was the
current search engine.
It seemed good enough.
And he said,
oh,
it's not to make
a search engine.
...is to make an AI.
Most of my discussions
have been with Larry Page.
We've talked in general
about their quest to
digitize all knowledge
and then develop true AI.
I mean,
we can create intelligent systems
if you have very large databases.
And books are actually probably
more valuable than all the other stuff
on the Internet because we have a
high standard for what we put in books.
The computer industry
and its implications in terms
of information technology
is a multi-trillion dollar.
Part of the economy.
It will be,
you know,
the basis of everything
we do in the future.
What Watson showed was
you can take a very large,
very messy set of data and if
you can use those inputs correctly
you can actually answer
really sophisticated questions.
And certainly the presence of
large amounts of data on the internet
is going to be as much an input
for machines as it is for people.
Well we really will
need to tap that.
...is computer systems that
can understand natural language.
And natural language understanding
is actually coming along very well.
IBM's Watson is a very good
example of the current state
of the art in computers
understanding natural language.
Because not only did
Watson have to understand
the convoluted language
in the Jeopardy query,
which includes metaphors and
similes and puns and riddles and jokes,
but it got its knowledge to respond
to the query from actually reading
200 million pages of
natural language documents,
including all of Wikipedia and
several other encyclopedias.
And when you see a computer
play better than we ever could,
it's one of those moments
where you realize,
oh,
yes,
the world really is different.
An IBM supercomputer named
Watson has won the first ever
Jeopardy quiz show competition,
starring a computer as a player.
The Google Book Project has,
in a sense,
trying to make that
universal library,
which could then be read by an
AI or a Watson-like supercomputer.
By 2045,
we'll have expanded,
according to my calculations,
the intelligence and capability of the
human machine civilization a billion-fold.
So that's such a
profound transformation,
such a singular transformation,
that we call it
the singularities.
Now,
this is not yet inside
my body or brain.
It may as well be.
I'm very dependent on it.
I think this is
part of who I am.
Ultimately this kind of
device will be the size of blood
cells and will go inside
our body to keep us healthy,
go inside our brains,
put our brains
directly on the internet,
give us direct access to
the entire library of all books.
AI is just a religion.
It doesn't matter.
What's really happening is real world
examples from real people who entered there.
Answers their trivia,
their experiences into some online
database is actually just a giant
puppet theater repackaging inputs
from real people who are forgotten.
We're pretending
they aren't there.
This is something I really want people to
see that this the insane structure of modern
finance is exactly the same as the insane
structure of modern culture on the internet.
They're precisely the same.
It's an attempt to gather all
the information into a high castle,
optimize the world and pretend.
That all the people information
came from don't deserve anything.
That it's all the same mistake.
Google search is going to be assisted
intelligence and not artificial intelligence.
In my mind,
I think of search as this beautiful symphony
between the user and the search engine.
And we make music together.
Since 1995, we have published exact
facsimiles of the handwritten works of Kafka
One of the main themes in Kafka's
work is the tension between the individual
and the institutions and
systems which try to control him
EFORE THE LAW READ
OM THE TRIAL 1962
EFORE THE LAW READ B
Orson Well OM "The Trial" 1962
FORE THE LAW READ BY
ORSON WELL OM THETRIAL 1962
In his famous
"Before the Law" story
a peasant, who is an ignorant fool
from the countryside and a coward
approaches the city gates and the gatekeeper
says to him "I am the master here"
And the mere fact that he
says that produces authority
Therefore the question of whether
he really does have any power
can only be answered
by actually taking action
The man tries to peer
through the entrance.
He had been taught that the law
should be accessible to every man.
Do not attempt to enter
without my permission,
says the guard.
So it is actually only a
small step from Kafka
to the confrontation
with Google Book Search
This tale is told during
this story called The Trial.
I've been surprised at the
level of controversy there,
because...
ERGEY BRIN FOUNDER, GOOGLE
there's nobody else who has attempted it at
our scale or who is really working on it.
So,
and I feel like we had a number of
technical challenges which we've overcome.
There was this legal dispute
which we have settlement,
a settlement was proposed,
at least that we jointly agreed to with
the authors and publishers and so forth.
But anyway,
it remains somewhat
controversial.
So...
Yeah,
I'm surprised at the amount
of resistance that's had,
but ultimately I'm optimistic
that we're going to be successful.
It's important to
understand that the
Google Books settlement was
negotiated by a small number of people
claiming to represent authors and
claiming to represent publishers.
But not every author and not
every publisher was in the room.
So once the
settlement's announced,
settlement and give them a
chance to opt out if they don't like the
settlement or to give them a chance
to object to the terms of the settlement.
and give them a chance to opt
out if they don't like the settlement
or to give them a chance to
object to the terms of the settlement.
quickly realised that the Google
Book Settlement would have an effect
on the copyright situation in
the Federal Republic of Germany
considered that totally unacceptable,
because no one had negotiated with us
We decided that we would
launch a public petition
called the Heidelberg Petition
and within two to three weeks
we had all the major author
Müller was honored
with the Nobel Prize.
And so there was
a snowball effect
Whether it's a slim
paperback or a fat doorstopper
more and more books are available
to read in their entirety on the Internet
Google have uploaded over ten
million titles and that is just the start
But this is something that
outrages many European authors
The internet - thieves' paradise. Digital
revolution - the spirit of rebellion
Access for everyone - for
free, forever and everywhere
Google is now realising our
ancient dream of a universal library
As nice as it sounds, total
digitisation may have big losers
The goal was to get the
German government to take actio
The German government believes that there
must be a place for copyright on the Internet
That's why we are opposed
to the scanning of books
without any copyright
protections as Google has done
The German government is determined
to defend the rights of German authors
It was like a bushfire, which
suddenly erupts and spreads
And I have to say that I was assisted
by the President of the Republic
IEAN-NC INEN FORMER
DIREC ORT FRENCH LIBR
The President of the Republic
and one or two of his aides
shared the view that this
was an important challenge
Les priorités du grand emprunt
We will not allow our cultural heritage
to be taken away by a large corporation
No matter how nice they may be, important
they may be or American they may be
The first time I realized Google
scanned my book was 2009,
November.
Actually,
my lawyer called me and he said,
do you know your book be
scanned by Google Book?
[148.08mln] SZSE
B SHARES 4425.70
SZSE B SHARES
4425.70 37 87 0.85%
SHARES 4425.70
37.87 0.85% [90.28ml BF
70 37.87 0.85%
[90.28mln] Baoshan
0.85% [90.28mln]
Baoshan Steel 8.12
0.28mln] Baoshan
Steel 8.12 10.16 1.9
Baoshan Steel
8.12 0.16 1.93% [218
el 8.12 0.16 1.93%
[218.83mln] Sinop
0.16 1.93% [218.83mln]
Sinopec Corp Bi
The reader,
they can search my book by the
keyword and made maybe 100,
around 100 keyword.
But I remember the most ridiculous
keyword of my book is the bed,
B-E-D,
and telephone.
That's two words I
remember and made me laugh.
So this is not
intellectual at all.
Me and my lawyer decide...
So Google,
my lawyer asked
60,000 something like that.
My journalist friends said,
I even don't want to
tell people I know you.
Why you ask such low money?
So I wrote this blog at
that night and I go sleep.
And when I wake up,
it's like 400 messages
at my blog said,
damage this girl
and this girl's bitch,
blah,
really disgusting,
horrible message.
I become a public
enemy after the.
Google said they
will leave China.
And also Chinese young people
started sending flowers to Google's office,
which made even my
best friend confused.
They said,
is the government
sending you to sue Google?
I was a victim. I discovered that my
whole book had been scanned by Google
So I decided to investigate
en I found out about this
American concept called "snippe
3 187
They extract a few lines from
the book for you to read online.
That works for American books
because the writing is horizontal
But they applied this same
snippet method to Japanese books
Unfortunately the majority of
Japanese books are written vertically
So what they display as a "snippet'
cannot be read as a sentence
So Google's snippets are
meaningless in Japanese
Playboy magazine is full of
pictures of nude young girls
300F9
which doesn't have
much to do with journalism
But Japanese Playboy - maybe the
American one too - has a spirit of defiance
When no one else will write
about something, they will take it on
That is why they got
interested in this story
EAR 20
They told me "This is
a job that only you can
do, Akashi!" So we
started publishing articles 20
Before the court is
the plaintiff's motion to
approve the settlement
as fair and reasonable.
Numerous materials
have been submitted.
Did anyone count up
the number of objections?
We have in the range of 500.
Thank you.
I flew to New York
and it was very exciting.
There were
25 outside parties that...
made presentations
to Judge Chin,
and there were 500
objections for him to read.
Judge basically said,
I'm not going to
rule from a bench,
but people were
hanging on every word.
This is a fascinating
turning point,
actually,
in the whole history of knowledge
and of access to knowledge.
And it was being
played out in a New York
courtroom before Judge
Denny Chin in the Southern
Federal District
Court of New York.
We thought just in
case we don't get in
we'll be the first to arrive
and get a seat on the front row
I confirm that one of my
books has been digitally
scanned by Google
without my permission.
Because this act is a clear
violation of the copyright law of Japan,
I have asked the Metropolitan
Police Department of Japan
to criminally charge Google
and its CEO for this violation.
The court's decision
was to a considerable
extent going to determine
the future of books,
of digital books.
The proposed settlement
results in a de facto monopoly on
information and an intensification
of media concentration on Google.
As a result,
the right of free
access to information,
as well as the existing
cultural diversity,
in both Germany and Europe,
will be usurped.
Would it be basically in
the hands of commercial
speculators whose responsibility
was to their shareholders?
Or would it be organized
for the public good?
There was a risk of monopolization
there that the Department of Justice saw.
The proposed settlement would
establish a marketplace in which only
one competitor would have
authority to use a vast array of works.
The risk was that
Google could basically hold
the whole world hostage to...
The price of access to these books and
because no one else would have a license,
no one else would have a
corpus like the corpus they had,
we'd have to pay whatever
they wanted to charge.
The core concerns
seem to be that this would
diminish the availability
to read books in private.
That is not true.
This service would be
available at public libraries.
You can walk into your
neighborhood library.
You can sit down at
a free access terminal,
anonymously.
You can search
for and read a book.
And if you want to
look at it at home,
then what?
Well,
if you want to
look at it at home,
that may present an issue.
Here's the rub.
This is a tension between
requirements for security that are insisted
on in order not to have these
works be sort of freely disseminated.
In my view...
The Google Books search
settlement is no different from the piracy
cases in which the internet and
digital technology are abused.
I strongly urge the court to
reject the proposed settlement.
I remember there being
a Japanese writer there,
and the language was very vivid.
It was as though,
you know,
as copyright was
going to be swept away,
and that copyright was
going to be destroyed.
approval of the
settlement was going to,
you know,
make the United States out of
compliance with treaty obligations.
There's a real risk that should
the court approve the settlement,
members of the World
Trade Organization will
initiate settlement
proceedings against the U.S.
government.
And if the U.S.
government were to
lose such proceedings,
which is a very
real possibility,
Our partners would be entitled to impose
trade sanctions against the United States.
You don't use words
like that very often.
It wasn't kind of like,
oh gee,
there are these issues and
we're concerned about something.
It was like,
this violates a treaty
How can the judge do something
that's going to violate a treaty?
This is crazy.
I am not going to rule today.
There's just too much to digest.
I will reserve decision.
There's much to think about.
Arise.
And then Judge
Chin thought about it.
He thought about it,
and he thought about it.
Google is a flagship American
company which makes
a lot of money for
America all over the world
and so we were worried that the court might
deliver a politically-motivated judgement
He took a very long time.
Every morning I
got up and I thought,
what is...
Is Judge Chin going to
announce his decision today?
And when he finally did,
I myself felt thrilled because the court
actually refused to sanction the settlement.
Then Google Book
Search could not take place,
at least according to
Google's original business plan.
U.S.
Circuit Judge Denny Chin
said the creation of the Universal
Library would benefit many
but would simply go too far.
Chin said the settlement of a class action
lawsuit that the company reached with U.S.
authors and publishers would
grant Google significant rights
to exploit entire books without
permission of copyright owners.
Chin also said the deal
gives Google a significant
advantage over competitors
and it would be rewarding it.
for engaging in wholesale copying of
copyrighted works without permission.
expected that this would be
the outcome. I wasn't surpris
Of course I was nappy
that it turned out this way but
I didn't crack open the
champagne or anything like that
I don't know Judge
Chin, but I salute him
as an example of the remarkable
independence of the American judicial system
Despite all the formidable
financial power of Google
he quietly ruled that the agreements
drawn up by this Mountain View firm
were invalid, baseless
and inappropriate
I think you could read
the decision by Judge
Chen as a defeat of
the screen by the book.
But this is a long war.
This is one battle.
and um
Whatever triumph there might
have been for books is going to
be short-lived because the
screen will ultimately triumph.
They spent several months
trying to negotiate a new settlement,
couldn't reach a new settlement
that was mutually acceptable,
so they're going to
have to go to trial.
Baidu,
China's search engine giant,
has been blamed by Chinese writers
for participating in copyright violation.
This is because the website offers
free online excerpts of stories and books.
without the author's
prior approval.
I think very late March
or early April of 2011,
we purged the site of about
2.8 million files that we believed
might be copyright infringing
within a period of 72 hours.
I think a good number of them
were books or chapters of books.
We then implemented a rule
where no one could upload anything
of more than 1,000 Chinese
characters without it being...
Manually inspected for
copyright infringement or
automatically inspected
for copyright infringement.
The problem is that then people
started uploading parts of books
in 1,000 character increments
so that they would avoid detection.
So there are always people
who want to abuse the system.
The question is,
has Google already been able
to make its search engine better?
Because of the Google Books
corpus and the scanning of
20 million books,
I think the answer
to that is yes.
The question of whether
large Internet companies are
making our lives easier
or gaining power over us,
I think it presents the kind of false
binary because they're doing both.
I mean,
if they were not
making our lives easier,
no one would be
using their services.
This is the tricky,
complicated question
that we'll have to...
face down the road.
I mean,
all of them are
making our lives easier.
I mean,
they're making products cheaper.
They're making our commute
less bothersome and more exciting.
Google will be supplying us
with glasses that will augment
reality and tell us about
where our friends are in the city.
They'll tell us the weather.
They'll tell us everything.
The question is what
would the trade-offs be?
And no one has asked
what happens with all of the
Information that would
pass through Google glasses.
I mean,
surely it will be
stored somewhere.
Surely Google will
not be discarding it,
because they will need to
know what it is that I've seen
yesterday so that they can
customize what I see today even better.
But then the question is,
would the National Security Agency be
able to go to Google and ask for that data,
ask for everything I've seen
through my Google glasses?
And if that would be the case,
then the question should be,
do we actually want
to have a society where
citizens are burying CCTV
cameras on their heads.
I can see why many people view Google or
the Internet as some kind of "Big Brother"
controlling everything, just as Wells
wrote in his science fiction many years ago
But things are much
simpler thanthat
The Internet is nothing
more than a medium
that offers everyone better access to
information, entertainment and knowledge
Getting to a better system
where people are rewarded
for their information
contributions to the world,
getting to that system
from where we are,
where people are
expected to get by with less,
that's going to be a hard transition
and they might involve government.
but they might involve
the big companies.
And the reason why is that the big
companies like Google and Amazon and
all the rest are shooting themselves
in the foot with what we're doing,
because what we're doing
is shrinking the economy.
I mean,
I don't know.
My concern is not so much with the
direction in which Google or Facebook,
for that matter,
want to take the world.
My concern is with the fact that it's Google
and Facebook taking us in that direction.
You can't just argue that
this serves the common good
If I go into the Deutsche
Bank, steal all the
money and distribute
it on the streets and say
"Look how many unemployed people I am helping!
Look, there aren't any beggars anymore"
It's still a bank robbery!
Do you understand?
Our current policy is to open up the library and to
make it part of this really very ambitious project,
more ambitious I
think than Google's,
which we call the
Digital Public
Library of America.
You know I think that we
owe a great deal to Google.
I can't imagine that
this digital public library
of America would ever
have gotten off the ground
had Google not started
to race ahead with its own
version of digitization
on this massive scale.
However,
you know,
Google,
wonderful as it is,
is not familiar with the books.
For example,
Walt Whitman's
famous book of poems,
Leaves of Grass,
was catalogued under gardening.
I was very careful not to come across
as a kind of reactionary French chauvinist
You know, the Gallic cock
who struts about crowing
because he is upset
that in the 18th century
Louis XV abandoned America as
Napoleon did later with Louisiana!
Some of my opponents
claimed this to be true to
avoid responding to my
arguments, but it wasn't
I wanted to launch a European
library project as a response to Google
which I called 'Europeana
perfectly compatible
with Europeana and that
means soon we will
have a worldwide network,
a gigantic world library.
H.G.
Wells'
view of science and technology
was what sustained him
and sustained his ideas
throughout his whole life.
He had this sense that
if only we could get the
scientists and the technologists
working in the right way.
We could transform the world.
And he continued with that
belief up until the absolute
final disillusionment with
the entire human world,
with a book which he calls,
so fittingly,
Mind at the End of its Tether.
He felt that the whole evolutionary
process that he had been studying and
that what he felt was leading us to
something new and wonderful had failed.
And his last words were
that there was no way out.
or round or through.
Our world of self-delusion will perish
amidst its evasions and fortuities.
It is like a convoy lost
in darkness along an
unknown rocky coast
with quarrelling pirates
in the chart room and
savages clambering up
the sides of the ship
to plunder and do evil as
the whim may take them.
That is the rough outline of the more and
more jumbled movie on the screen before us.
There is no way out,
or round,
or through.